Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
José de Rivera papers
1930-1991
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
de Rivera, José
5.3 linear feet
The papers of sculptor José de Rivera date from 1930 to 1991 and measure 5.3 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical materials, letters, scattered personal business records, commission files, art work including four sketchbooks, printed material, and photographs. One of the commission files includes a motion picture film.
Provenance
The José de Rivera papers were donated by the artist and the Grace Borgenicht Gallery in 1982. Additional material was donated by José de Rivera's son, Joseph A. Ruiz II, in 1998.
Separated Material
In 1970, José de Rivera loaned some papers for microfilming on Reel N70-32. These materials are not described in the container listing of this finding aid.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Biographical Note
José de Rivera (1904-1985) worked primarily in New York as an abstract expressionist sculptor known for twisting steel or bronze bands into space-defining three-dimensional shapes.
José A. Ruiz was born on September 18, 1904 in West Baton Rouge, Louisiana, the son of Joseph and Honorine Montamat Ruiz. He would later take the surname of his maternal grandmother, de Rivera. Early in his life his family moved to New Orleans where his father was a sugar mill engineer on a plantation. De Rivera became adept at repairing machinery and doing blacksmith work with his father. Shortly after completing high school in 1922, de Rivera moved to Chicago where he was employed in foundries and machine shops as a pipe fitter and tool and die maker. His 1926 marriage to Rose Covelli ended in divorce.
Beginning in 1928 de Rivera attended night drawing classes conducted at the Studio School by painter John W. Norton. De Rivera was impressed by the Egyptian collections at the Field Museum. The work of Mondrian, Brancusi, and Georges Vantongerloo also exerted a strong influence on him. In 1932, he traveled through southern Europe and North Africa visiting Spain, Italy, France, Greece, and Egypt. Upon his return to the United States he decided to become a sculptor.
From 1937-1938, de Rivera was employed by the Works Progress Administration-Federal Art Project and created the sculpture Flight for the Newark, New Jersey airport. During World War II, he first served in the U.S. Army Corps from 1942 to 1943. For the following three years, he designed and constructed ship models used as training aids in the U. S. Navy.
De Rivera's first solo exhibition was in 1946 in New York at the Mortimer Levitt Gallery. In 1953, de Rivera taught sculpture at Brooklyn College. For the following three years, he was a critic in sculpture at Yale University and taught at the School of Design at North Carolina State College from 1957 to 1960. De Rivera married Lita Jeronimo in 1955.
In 1961 de Rivera was given a retrospective exhibition at the Whitney Museum of American Art. One of his most notable works Infinity was commissioned by the Smithsonian Institution for the front of its newly built Museum of History and Technology in 1963.
José de Rivera died on March 19, 1985 in New York City.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of sculptor José de Rivera date from 1930 to 1991 and measure 5.3 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical materials, letters, scattered personal business records, commission files, art work including four sketchbooks, printed material, and photographs. One of the commission files includes a motion picture film.
Biographical material consists of a biographical account, resumé, military service records, an interview transcript, certificates, addresses, and miscellaneous notes and writings.
Twenty-nine folders of letters are primarily from de Rivera's patron, attorney Howard Goldsmith, but also include single letters from Marcel Breuer, John Canaday, Emlen Etting, Dag Hammarskjold, and G. Vantongerloo.
Scattered personal business records include rental records, sculpture inventories, a contract, receipts, and miscellaneous records.
Commission files contain letters, contracts, receipts, clippings, blueprints, miscellaneous printed material, and photographs concerning several of de Rivera's commissions, including Brussels Construction for the Brussels Universal and International Exhibition, his sculpture for the 1964 New York World's Fair, and Infinity, commissioned for the Smithsonian. A file for Construction #73 completed for the American Iron and Steel Institute also contains a reel of 16mm motion picture film.
Art work consists of four sketchbooks, drawings, and geometric collages including detached cut out shapes.
Printed material includes primarily clippings and exhibition announcements and catalogs. There is also a copy of the book José de Rivera Constructions by Dore Ashton and Joan M. Marter. Photographs are of de Rivera, miscellaneous art-related events, his studio, his art works, and of miscellaneous exhibition installations. Commission files also contain photographs.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 7 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1942-1984 (Box 1; 11 folders)
Series 2: Letters, 1938-1988 (Box 1; 29 folders)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, 1947-1984 (Box 1; 11 folders)
Series 4: Commission Files, 1955-1977 (Box 1-2, 6-7, OV 10; 1.0 linear feet)
Series 5: Art Work, 1960-1984 (Box 2, 6, OV 8; 0.9 linear feet)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1931-1991 (Box 2-4, 6; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 7: Photographs, 1930-1985 (Box 4-7, OV 9-OV 10; 1.7 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Ashton, Dore; Marter, Joan M.; American Iron and Steel Institute; Smithsonian Institution; Exposition universelle et internationale--(1958 :Brussels, Belgium); New York World's Fair--(1964-1965)
Subjects-Topical:
Artists' studios--Photographs; Hispanic American artists; Sculptors--New York (State)--New York--Interviews; Sculpture, American--New York (State)--New York
Types of Materials:
Blueprints; Collages; Drawings; Interviews; Motion pictures (visual works); Photographs; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Transcripts
Names:
Goldsmith, Howard
Series descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1942-1984, Series 1:; (Box 1; 11 folders)
  Biographical material consists of a biographical account, resumé, military records documenting de Rivera's service in both the U. S. Army and the Navy, a transcript of an interview in which de Rivera describes his development as an artist, an Art Directors Club certificates of merit, a certificate of fitness, an honorary doctorate diploma, files and lists of addresses, an annotated wall calendar, and miscellaneous notes and writings.
  - Biographical Account and Resumé, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Military Service Records, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Interview Transcript, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Art Directors Club Certificate of Merit; Certificate of Fitness, 1957-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Honorary Doctorate Diploma from Washington University at St. Louis, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Files of Addresses, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Address Lists, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annotated Wall Calendar, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Writings, 1955-1956, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letters, 1938-1988, Series 2:; (Box 1; 29 folders)
  Letters are primarily from de Rivera's patron, Howard Goldsmith, but include single letters from John Canaday, Emlen Etting, Dag Hammarskjold, and G. Vantongerloo. There is also a letter of recommendation from Marcel Breuer and an invitation from the Lyndon Johnson White House.
  - Unidentified Correspondents, 1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Abrams - American Enka Corporation, 1967-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Iron and Steel Institute - Art Source, 1953-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Baits - Benson, 1956-1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Borgenicht - Brown, 1946-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Campbell - Coughlin, 1951-1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - David Industries - Everett Ellin Gallery, 1955-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Feldman - Fuerst, 1959-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Galérie ClauDeBernard - Gottscho-Schleisner, 1946-1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Howard Goldsmith, 1960-1975, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
  - Hammarskjold - Humphreys, 1946-1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Ilg - Isaac delgado Museum of Art, 1954-1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - JG Furniture Company - Johnson, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Kahn - Kunstadter, 1955-1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Lachner - Lathrop, 1960-1983 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Lea and Edwards - Levi, 1940-1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Malcolm - Museum of Modern Art, 1939-1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Nathan - New York World's Fair, 1938-1973 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - North Carolina State College at Raleigh - North Eastern Pharmaceutical and Chemical Company (NEPACCO), 1957-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 110 William Street Corporation - Port of New York Authority, 1938-1984 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Randall and Associates - Rubin, 1953-1978 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Scher - Syracuse University, 1958-1973 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Tarica, Ltd. - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1939-1983 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Walch - Welding Engineer Magazine, 1955-1974 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art - Wichita State University, 1952-1974 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Zalud Marine Corporation, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Personal Business Records, 1947-1984, Series 3:; (Box 1; 11 folders)
  Personal business records consist of a general release from de Rivera to William Kaufman acting on behalf of Helen Eisenstein, rent records for de Rivera's assistant, sculptor Roy Gussow, inventories of sculpture including small sketches of some of the works, a contract concerning the Taller Ediciones JB book about de Rivera's art work, and miscellaneous records including receipts for the sale of art work.
  - General Release from de Rivera to William Kaufman Acting on Behalf of Helen Eisenstein, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Rent Records for Roy Gussow, 1964-1983 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Sculpture Inventory, 1976-1981, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 43-45)
  - Taller Ediciones JB: Book about the Art Work of José de Rivera, 1979-1984, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 46-47)
  - Receipts for the Sale of Art Work, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous Records, 1947-1984, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Commission Files, 1955-1977, Series 4:; (Box 1-2, 6-7, OV 10; 1.0 linear feet)
  Commission files contain letters, contracts, receipts, clippings, blueprints, miscellaneous printed material, and photographs concerning de Rivera's projects including the Brussels Construction for the Brussels Universal and International Exhibition and his sculpture for the 1964 New York World's Fair. Of primary significance is the file concerning Infinity, commissioned for the plaza in front of the Smithsonian Museum of History and Technology, now the National Museum of American History. This file contains a detailed photographic record of the construction and installation of this work which, in 1967, was the largest abstract sculpture commissioned by the government. Also of note is the file for Construction #73 for the American Iron and Steel Institute which contains a reel of 16mm motion picture film recording the movements of the sculpture.
  - Wishing Star, Statler Hilton Hotel, Dallas, Texas, 1955-1957, (7 folders) (Box 1, Folder 50-56)
  - Brussels Construction, Brussels Universal and International Exhibition, 1957-1970, (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 57-62)
  - Sculpture for New York World's Fair, 1962-1964, (3 folders; Oversized Material Housed in OV 10) (Box 1, Folder 63-65)
  - Infinity, Smithsonian Museum of History and Technology, 1963-1977, (19 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 66-84)
  - Construction #73, "Steel Century Two," American Iron and Steel Institute, 1964-1965, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
  - Construction #105, Rochester Institute of Technology, 1967-1971, (Oversized Material Housed in OV 10) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sculpture for the Popejoy Concert Hall, University of New Mexico at Albuquerque, 1969-1970, (Oversized Material Housed in OV 10) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Construction #150, Washington Square, Lansing, Michigan, 1973, (4 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6 and OV 10) (Box 2, Folder 9-12)
  - An Oversized Schematic Drawing for Construction #150, Washington Square, Lansing, Michigan, 1973, (from Box 2, Folder 9) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Two Oversized Photographs of Infinity, Smithsonian Museum of History and Technology, 1963, (from Box 1, Folder 73) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - An Oversized Blueprint for New York World's Fair, 1964, (from Box 1, Folder 66) (Box OV 10)
  - Three Oversized Blueprints and a Schematic Drawing for Construction #105, Rochester Institute of Technology, 1967, (from Box 2, Folder 7) (Box OV 10)
  - An Oversized Blueprint for the Sculpture for the Popejoy Concert Hall, University of New Mexico at Albuquerque, 1969, (from Box 2, Folder 8) (Box OV 10)
  - An Oversized Blueprint for Construction #150, Washington Square, Lansing, Michigan, 1973, (from Box 2, Folder 9) (Box OV 10)
- Art Work, 1960-1984, Series 5:; (Box 2, 6, OV 8; 0.9 linear feet)
  Art work consists of four sketchbooks, drawings, primarily of designs for sculpture and brooches, and some scattered schematic drawings for unidentified projects, and geometric collages including detached cut out shapes.
  - Sketchbook 1, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Sketchbook 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Sketchbook 3, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Sketchbook 4, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Drawings on Newsprint, 1960-1975, undated, (3 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 2, Folder 17-19)
  - designs for Sculpture, 1975-1976, undated, (12 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 2, Folder 20-31)
  - Geometric Drawings, 1966, undated, (10 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6 and OV 8) (Box 2, Folder 32-41)
  - Geometric Collages, undated, (2 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6 and OV 8) (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
  - designs for Brooches, 1978-1984, undated, (14 folders) (Box 2, Folder 44-57)
  - Cut-Out Abstract Shapes, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous Art Work, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Ten Oversized Drawings on Newsprint, 1961-1964, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 19) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Fourteen Oversized designs for Sculpture, 1976, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 31) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Eighteen Oversized Geometric Drawings, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 41) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Four Oversized Geometric Collages, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 43) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - An Oversized Cut-Out Shape, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 58) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Five Oversized Schematic Drawings for Unidentified Projects, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 59) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Six Oversized Geometric Drawings, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 41) (Box OV 8)
  - Two Geometric Collages, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 43) (Box OV 8)
- Printed Material, 1931-1991, Series 6:; (Box 2-4, 6; 1.5 linear feet)
  Printed material consists of clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs for de Rivera and others, press releases, programs, brochures, booklets, a copy of the book José de Rivera Constructions by Dore Ashton and Joan M. Marter, and reproductions of art work. Miscellaneous printed material includes a first day cover envelope dated honoring Stuart Davis.
  - Clippings, 1931-1987, undated, (25 folders) (Box 2, Folder 60-84)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1946-1991, undated, (35 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 1-35)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Others, 1970-1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Press Releases, 1956-1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
  - Programs, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Brochures, 1971-1984, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Booklets, 1968-1980, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 41-43)
  - Book José de Rivera Constructions by Dore Ashton and Joan M. Marter, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Reproductions of Art Work, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1964-1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - An Oversized Exhibition Announcement, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 1) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Two Oversized Brochures, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 40) (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Photographs, 1930-1985, Series 7:; (Box 4-7, OV 9-OV 10; 1.7 linear feet)
  Photographs are of de Rivera including one with Burgoyne Diller, miscellaneous art-related events, his studio, his art works, and of miscellaneous exhibition installations at the Grace Borgenicht Gallery and of his 1972 Retrospective at the Whitney Museum of American Art. Of special interest are the photographs concerning Flight and The Cavalryman which document the stages of de Rivera's work on these sculptures.
  - Photographs of José de Rivera, 1937-1980, undated, (6 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 4-9)
  - Photographs of de Rivera in his Studio, 1958-1960, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of de Rivera at Miscellaneous Events, 1969-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of de Rivera's Studio, 1985, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Female Figure], undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Abstract Form], undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6 and Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Abstract Human Form], undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6 and Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Abstract Female Form], undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Abstract Sculptures in Marble], undated, (2 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Abstract Sculptures in Metal], undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Model for Playground Sculpture and Miscellaneous Wall-Mounted Sculpture], undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Miscellaneous Stainless Steel Sculpture, undated, (6 folders) (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7 and OV 10) (Box 4, Folder 21-26)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Miscellaneous Art Work, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Bust and Owl, 1930, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6 and Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Form Synthesis [Human Form], 1930 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Untitled Human Form in Metal], 1930 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Form Synthesis [Bust], 1935, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Head, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Flight, 1937, (3 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 33-35)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Bas-Relief for Soviet Pavilion, New York World's Fair, 1939, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Biomorphic Form (Life), 1940, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
  - Photographs of Art Work: The Cavalryman, El Paso, Texas, 1940, (7 folders) (Box 4, Folder 39-45)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Yellow and Metal-Surfaced Sculpture, 1940-1942 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Blue, White, Yellow, 1942, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Black and Red Construction, 1942, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Black, Yellow, and Red Construction, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Model Ship designs for the U. S. Navy, circa 1944, (Oversized Material Housed in OV 9) (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Painting Black Yellow Red, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction in Black and Yellow, 1945-1949, (2 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 52-53)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Yellow, Black, 1946, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Light Sculpture for Andrew Geller Shoe Salon, 1947, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Aluminum Sculpture with Red, Black, Yellow Pigment], 1947-1950, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Copper Construction in Circular Shape], 1949 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Copper Construction in Open Shape], 1949 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Photographs of Art Work: En Route, Dining Salon of the S. S. Argentina, 1949, (2 folders) (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 59-60)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction in Red and Black, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Bas-Relief, 1950, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #11, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #13 and Construction #15, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Black and Red Construction, 1951, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction in Blue and Black [I], 1951, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction in Blue and Black [II], 1951, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Stainless Steel Construction], 1951, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction in Yellow and Black, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction in Black and Yellow, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Photographs of Art Work: [Pin], 1953 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #2, Construction #4, and Construction #5, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Copper Relief, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #34 and Construction #37, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Working Models for Yale Sculpture, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #1, Homage to the World of Minkowski, 1955, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 76-78)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Sculpture for the American Enka Corporation, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Continuum, 711 Third Avenue, New York City, 1956, (2 folders) (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 80-81)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #25, Construction #27, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #30, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #41, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Bronze Relief, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #44, Construction #46, and Construction #47, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #50, Construction #57, and Construction #62, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #64 and Construction #65, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #66, Annenberg School of Communications, University of Pennsylvania, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Sculpture for 110 William Street Corporation, New York City, 1959, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Photographs of Art Work: Construction #67 and Construction #70, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 91)